Guide to the Witold Gombrowicz Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1944-1970, n.d.; Series I; 5.01; (12 boxes)
  - Hagenau, Gerda
    See: S. Fischer Verlag, box 10, folder 354
  - Hamilton, Alastair, 1965-67 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    Includes a letter from RG
    See also: Neske (Firm), box 8, 273-275
  - Harcourt, Brace & World, 1962-66 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1964-65 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Harpprecht, Klaus, 1967 Nov 23 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Härtling, Peter
    See: Neske (Firm), box 8, folder 268
  - Hartung, Rudolf
    See: Neue Rundschau, box 8, folder 277
    See: Limes Verlag Max Niedermayer, box 7, folder 231
  - Helsingin Kaupungin Teatteri
    See: Arlecchino Teaterförlag Bertil Bodén, box 1, folder 7
  - Hémery, Jean-Claude, 1967-69 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Höllerer, Walter
    See: Literarisches Colloquium Berlin, box 7, folder 234
    See: Technische Universität Berlin, box 11, folder 401
  - Hordynski, Jerzy
    See: Ernesto R. Sábato, Matilde Sábato, box 10, folder 356
  - Hunt, John Clinton
    See: Congress for Cultural Freedom, box 3, folder 69
  - Hunter College
    See: Series II. Writings, "Gombrowicz: An Interview" by Bettina Knapp, box 16, folder 561
  - "I" general, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Iglesias, Ignacio
  - Insel-Verlag, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Instytut Literacki
    See: Jerzy Giedroyc, Box 4, Folder 120-122
  - International Copyright Bureau Ltd, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 168)
    Includes a letter from a translator Urszula Pearce
  - International Bureau voor Auteurrecht, 1963-66 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Iwaszkiewicz, Jaroslaw, 1946-68, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 170-172)
  - Janta, Aleksander, 1960-69 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    See also: Series V. Writings by Others About Gombrowicz, Working file (photocopies of letters to WG, dated 1950-67), box 35, folder 1017
  - Jalard, Michel-Claude
  - Javet, Pierre
    See: Julliard (Firm), box 6, folder 189-190
  - Jelenski, Constantin
    See also: Geneviève Serreau, box 10, folder 370
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1956-57 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 175-176)
    Includes letters from Zygmunt Michalowski to CJ.
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    See also: Anna Posner, box 8, folder 307
    See also: Wiener Hefte, box 11, folder 426
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1961-62 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    Includes a postcard signed also by Alicja Giangrande, Zofia Romanowicz, Kazimierz Romanowicz, B. Romanowicz, Ewa Radzikowska [?], [Jan] Lebenstein
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1963-65 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    See also: Radio Free Europe, box 9, folder 322
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    See also: Ivan Nagel, box 8, folder 265
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    Includes WG's letter to Kobunsha Co. Ltd.
  - Jelenski, Constantin, 1969-70 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    See also: Radio Free Europe, 1965-69, n.d., box 9, folder 323
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, Constantin Jelenski, box 59, folder 1498
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, Constantin Jelenski, box 59, folder 1531
  - Jelenski, Constantin, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 185)
    Includes biographical notes by WG
  - Jenne, Beniamin Jozef, 1967 Jun 1 (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - John Calder (Publishers)
    See: Calder and Boyars, Ltd, box 2, folder 55
  - Jonathan Cape (Firm), 1969 Jan 28 (Box 6, Folder 187)
  - Jordan, Fred
    See: Grove Press, folder 149, 152, 154, 155
  - Jugoslovenska autorska agencija, 1963-69 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    Includes letter from Banque nationale de Yougoslavie and statement of account
  - Julliard (Firm), 1958-60 (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - Julliard (Firm), 1961-65 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    Includes correspondence with Sequana and royalty statement
    See also: Atlantic Monthly Press, box 1, folder 16
  - Julliard (Firm), 1966-67 (Box 6, Folder 191)
  - Julliard (Firm), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    Includes correspondence with Peter Lotschak; WG's note "Contrats signé par W. Gombrowicz avec Ed. Denoël"
  - Julliard (Firm), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    Includes copy of lawyer's opinion (enclosure)
    See also: Koukou Chanska, box 6, folder 212
  - Julliard (Firm), 1962-70 (Box 6, Folder 194)
    Contains: leaflet pertaining to Journal 1953-1956 (1964); royalty statements for 1962-70
  - "K" general, 1965-69 (Box 6, Folder 195)
  - Kagel, Mauricio, 1963 Dec (Box 6, Folder 196)
    Includes French translation of the letter
  - Kaluzynski, Zygmunt, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Kantor, Tadeusz, [1958] (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - Kijowski, Andrzej, 1969 Feb 6 (Box 6, Folder 199)
  - Kister, Hanna, 1967 May 10 (Box 6, Folder 200)
  - Knapp, Bettina Liebowitz
  - Kolukisa, Can
    See: Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), box 10, folder 381
  - Koscialkowska, Janina, 1967 Apr 5 (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Kosko, Allan, 1959-69 (Box 6, Folder 202-203)
    See also: Jelenski, Constantin, box 6, folder 184
    See also: JorgeLavelli, box 7, folder 224
  - Koszella, Leo, 1958-59 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Kotkowski, Gustaw, 1951 Apr 4 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1962-63 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    See also: Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), box 10, folder 207
  - Koukou Chanska, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 208)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Koukou Chanska, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    Includes WG's draft of a letter and third party letters
  - Koukou Chanska, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 213)
    Translations of WG's works have been removed and placed in Series II. Writings
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz's Papers, Koukou Chanska, box 59, folder 1499
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz's Papers, Koukou Chanska, box 59, folder 1532
  - Krance, Felicja, 1966-68 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - Kreuder, Ernst; Kreuder,Irene, 1967 Apr 4 (Box 7, Folder 215)
    Contains a letter written by Irene Kreuder and signed on behalf of her husband and herself
  - Kruntorad, Paul
    See: Wiener Hefte, box 11, folder 426
  - Kudo, Yukio, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 216)
  - Kukulczanka, Jadwiga
    See: Koukou Chanska, box 6, folders 206-213
  - Kultura
    See: Jerzy Giedroyc, box 4, folder 123
  - Kuncewiczowa, Maria Szczepanska, 1950-53 (Box 7, Folder 217)
    Includes: transcripts and translations of the letters, PEN Club's press announcement
  - Kusniewicz, Andrzej, 1959 Oct 8 (Box 7, Folder 218)
  - Kwiatkowski, Tadeusz, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 219)
  - "L" general, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 220)
  - Lachmann, Peter, 1960-62, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 221)
  - Landau, Ryszard, 1962-69 (Box 7, Folder 222)
  - Lang, Jack
    See: Festival Mondial du théâtre de Nancy, box 3, folder 102
  - Lavelli, Jorge, 1960-69, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 223-225)
    Includes a letter written jointly with Allan Kosko with annotations by other persons
    See also: Allan Kosko, box 6, folder 202
    See also: Jacques Robnard, box 9, folder 335
  - Lawrenson, T. E. (Thomas Edward), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - Lenica, Jan, 1967 May 2, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 227)
  - Leonhardt, Albrecht
    See: Albrecht Leonhardt Literary Agency, box 1, folder 3
  - Lepage, Jacques, 1968 Nov 4 (Box 7, Folder 228)
  - Lerici, Roberto, 1962 Dec 20 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    Contains a letter written on behalf of Lerici editori s.p.a.
    See also: Czytelnik (Firm), box 3, folder 74
  - Lettres Nouvelles
    See: Julliard (Firm), box 6, folder 189-194
    See: Maurice Nadeau, box 8, folder 262-264
    See: Geneviève Serreau, box 10, folder 370-371
  - Libella (Firm)
    See: Kazimierz Romanowicz, box 9, folder 337
  - Ligocka, Roma, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 230)
    Includes on the verso a letter by Jan Biczycki dated 1966 Aug 5
  - Limes Verlag Max Niedermayer, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - Lisinski, Michal, 1967-[69?] (Box 7, Folder 232)
    Includes press releases
  - Lisowski, Jerzy, 1960-62 (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Literarisches Colloquium Berlin, 1964-66 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    Includes a program of the session "Modernes Theater auf kleinen Bühnen"
  - Lötsch, Manfred
  - Lubomirska, Ada, 1963-65 (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - Lunds Universitet, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Lynch, Marta, 1964-69, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 237)
  - "M" general, 1969 Jan 5 (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - Macgibbon & Kee, 1959-66 (Box 7, Folder 239-241)
    Includes French translations of some letters and a draft of a letter
  - Makowiecka, Gabriela, 1966 Mar 3 (Box 7, Folder 242)
  - Malic, Zdravko, 1962-67 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    Includes the authorization for "Teatr 'Komedija'" of Zagreb.
  - Manguel, Alberto
    See: Editorial Galerna, box 3, folder 90
  - Mantel, Feliks, 1967 May 3 (Box 7, Folder 244)
  - March, Anna
    See: Edicions 62, box 3, folder 88
  - Marié, François, 1968-69 (Box 7, Folder 245)
  - Marsay, Pierre, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 246)
  - Massé, Claude, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 247)
  - Matillon, Janine, 1969 Mar (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - Mauersberg, Adam
    See: Witold Gombrowicz "Listy do Adama Mauersberga", box 35, folder 1029
  - Mayewski, Pawel, 1960-62 (Box 7, Folder 249)
    Includes photocopies of publications of letters, a page with a dedication probably removed from a book
  - MCA Inc., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - Messinger, Sylvie
    See: Belfond (Firm), box 1, folder 24-25
  - Mieroszewski, Juliusz, 1961-68 (Box 7, Folder 251)
  - Milosz, Czeslaw, 1961-69 (Box 7, Folder 252)
    One of the letters addressed also to RG
  - Missiroli, Mario, 1968 Jul 22 (Box 7, Folder 253)
  - Mitrani, Michel, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 254)
  - Le Monde (Box 7, Folder 255)
  - Mosbacher, Eric, 1961 Mar 29 (Box 7, Folder 256)
  - Moussault's Uitgeverij, 1960-67 (Box 7, Folder 257)
  - Mrozek, Slawomir, 1968 Jun 19 (Box 7, Folder 258)
    See also: Jerzy Giedroyc, box 4, folder 121
  - Muchnik, Jacobo, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 259)
    Written on behalf of Compañia General Fabril Editora
  - Münchner Kammerspiele
    See: Ivan Nagel, box 8, folder 265
  - Murat, Napoléon, 1968-70 (Box 7, Folder 260)
  - Mycielski, Zygmunt, 1961-67 (Box 7, Folder 261)
  - Nadeau, Maurice, 1958-61 (Box 8, Folder 262)
    See also: Théâtre de Bourgogne, box 11, folder 403
  - Nadeau, Maurice, 1962-65 (Box 8, Folder 263)
    Includes WG's draft of a preface to his plays
    See also: Series II. Writings, Kosmos, 1st version [written between 1961 Feb and 1963 Apr in Argentina], holograph corrected, typescript carbon corrected, box 12, folder 457
  - Nadeau, Maurice, 1966-68, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 264)
    Includes introduction to Entretiens avec Gombrowicz by MN
  - Nagel, Ivan, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 265)
  - Nakow, Andrzej, 1968-69 (Box 8, Folder 266)
  - Neske (Firm), 1958-59 (Box 8, Folder 267)
  - Neske (Firm), 1960-61 (Box 8, Folder 268)
  - Neske (Firm), 1962-64 (Box 8, Folder 269-270)
    Includes Polish translation of one letter
  - Neske (Firm), 1965 (Box 8, Folder 271)
  - Neske (Firm), 1966 (Box 8, Folder 272)
    Includes German translations of some WG's letters
  - Neske (Firm), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 273)
    Includes German and French translations of some letters
  - Neske (Firm), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 274)
    Includes French translations of some Günther Neske's letters
  - Neske (Firm), 1969, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 275)
    Includes French translations of some Günther Neske's letters, undated fragments and drafts
  - Neske (Firm), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 276)
    Contains prospectus of the film adaptation of Pornography ("Zalozenia opracowania filmowego powiesci Witolda Gombrowicza Pornografia ")
  - Nestler Peter
    See: Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst, box 3, folder 78-79
  - Neue Rundschau, 1966-67 (Box 8, Folder 277)
  - New American Library, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 278)
  - Nolit (Firm), 1963 Jul 2 (Box 8, Folder 279)
  - Nouveau Théâtre de Poche, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 280)
  - Nowak, Jan, 1967 May 2 (Box 8, Folder 281)
    See also: Radio Free Europe, box 9, folder 320-323
  - Nowakowski, Tadeusz, 1967 May 3 (Box 8, Folder 282)
  - "O" general, 1960 Apr 21 (Box 8, Folder 283)
  - Oceano, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 284)
  - Odier, Daniel, 1967 May 8 (Box 8, Folder 285)
  - Odrawaz-Pieniazek, Janusz, 1969 Feb 12 (Box 8, Folder 286)
  - Office de radiodiffusion-télévision française, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 287)
  - O'Keeffe, Timothy
    See: MacGibbon & Kee, box 7, folder 239-241
    See: Atlantic Monthly Press, box 1, folder 16
  - Orel, Elisabeth, 1957-66, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 288)
  - Orme, Alexandra
    - Orme, Alexandra, 1967-69 (Box 8, Folder 289)
      See also: Calder and Boyars, Ltd, box 2, folder 55
      See also: Kazimierz Wierzynski, box 11, folder 428
      See also: Series V. Writings by Others About Gombrowicz, Working file (photocopies of Alexandra Orme's letters to WG, dated 1950-56), box 35, folder 1020
      See also: Restricted Papers, box 137, folder 2474-2477
    - Formerly restricted correspondence, 1950-61 (Box 137, Folder 2477-2480)
  - Osadczuk, Bohdan; Osadczuk, Irena
    See: Series V. Writings by Others About Gombrowicz, "Listy Witolda Gombrowicza do Ireny i Bohdana Osadczukow," printed version, box 35, folder 1030
  - Österreichische Nationalbibliothek, 1964 Aug 6 (Box 8, Folder 290)
  - "P" general, 1960-69 (Box 8, Folder 291)
  - Paczowska, Maria; Paczowski, Bohdan, 1963-69, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 292-293)
    Include a letter dictated by WG to RG and written in phonetical Polish and letters with annotations by RG
  - Palester, Roman, 1967 May 12 (Box 8, Folder 294)
    See also: Radio Free Europe, box 9, folder 321-323
  - Panstwowy Teatr imienia Stefana Zeromskiego Kielce-Radom, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 295)
  - Panstwowy Instytut Wydawniczy (Firm)
    See: Janusz Gombrowicz, box 4, folder 129
  - Paola, Jorge di, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 296)
    Includes French translation of some letters and transcripts of illegible copies
    See also: Mariano Betelú, box 1, folders 29-33, box 2, folders 34-42
  - Paris Review, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 297)
  - Pawlikowski, Michal K., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 298)
  - PEN (Organization)
    See: Maria Szczepanska Kuncewiczowa, box 3, folder 217
  - Pérez Estremera, Manuel
  - Peterkiewicz, Jerzy, 1959-61 (Box 8, Folder 299)
  - Pietak, Stanislaw, 1961-62 (Box 8, Folder 300)
  - Piñera, Virgilio, 1959-68 (Box 8, Folder 301)
  - Pitol, Sergio, 1966-68, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 302)
    Includes letters written by SP on behalf of Departamento Editorial (Universidad Veracruzana), WG's directions concerning publication of Diario argentino and a page from the booklet published by Departamento Editorial
  - Plá, Roger, 1968-[69?] (Box 8, Folder 303)
  - Pochade, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 304)
  - Poets' and Painters' Press, 1969 Jul 23 (Box 8, Folder 305)
  - Polac, Michel, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 306)
  - Polak & Van Gennep
    See: Athenaeum - Polak & Van Gennep, box 1, folder 14
  - Posner, Anna, 1959-60, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 307)
  - Premio Marzotto Europa, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 308)
  - Premio Marzotto Europa - additional material, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 309)
    Contains a booklet "Premio Marzotto Europa" with annotations by RG and WG
  - Preuves, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 310)
    See also: François Bondy, box 2, folder 46
  - Prix International de Litterature Formentor, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 311)
    Includes WG's notes about the jury and a letter by Jaime Salinas
  - Przekrój
    See: Janusz Gombrowicz, boc 4, folder 128
  - Przyluski, Bronislaw, 1967 May 2 (Box 9, Folder 312)
  - Publicaçoes Dom Quixote, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 313)
  - Puig, Manuel, 1969 Apr (Box 9, Folder 314)
  - Quinzaine littéraire, 1967 Jul 30 (Box 9, Folder 315)
  - "R" General, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 316)
  - R. Piper & Co., 1966-68 (Box 9, Folder 317)
  - Radaelli, Sigfrido Augusto, 1967 Feb 24 (Box 9, Folder 318)
  - Radaelli, Paolo, 1968 Jun 22 (Box 9, Folder 319)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1956-59 (Box 9, Folder 320)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1960-62 (Box 9, Folder 321)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1963-64 (Box 9, Folder 322)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1965-69, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 323)
  - Radio Free Europe - additional material, 1961 Jun 6 (Box 9, Folder 324)
    Contains a copy of Free Europe Committee's "Plan for Post Termination Assistance"
  - Radiotelevisione italiana, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 325)
  - Rambures, Jean-Louis
    See: Réalités, box 9, folder 329
  - Rassegna internazionale dei teatri stabili, 1967-68 (Box 9, Folder 326)
  - Ravoni, Marcelo
    See: Feltrinelli editore, box 3, folders 98-99
  - Rawicki, Lech-Michel, 1968-69 (Box 9, Folder 327)
  - Read, Piers Paul, 1966-67 (Box 9, Folder 328)
  - Réalités, 1967 Dec 15 (Box 9, Folder 329)
  - Rellstab, Felix
    See: Theater am Neumarkt (Zürich, Switzerland), box 11, folder 402
  - Richter, Rudolf, 1961-68 (Box 9, Folder 330)
  - See also: Neske (Firm), box 8, folder 268, 271
  - Richter, Rudolf, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 331)
    Contains processing notes explaining absence of some letters
  - Rièse, Laure, 1968 Oct 24 (Box 9, Folder 332)
  - Ríos Patrón, José Luis, 1948-50 (Box 9, Folder 333)
  - Riva, Valerio
  - Robin, Pierre, n.y. Feb 27 (Box 9, Folder 334)
  - Robnard, Jacques, 1964-67 (Box 9, Folder 335)
    See also: Arlecchino Teatervörlag Bertil Bodén, box 1, folder 6
  - Rodriguez Monegal, Emir, 1967 May 19 (Box 9, Folder 336)
    Written on behalf of Mundo Nuevo. Revista de America Latina
  - Romanowicz, Kazimierz, 1960 Oct 27 (Box 9, Folder 337)
  - Romanowicz, Zofia, 1961 Jan 4 (Box 9, Folder 338)
  - Romero, Francisco A., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 339)
  - Ronconi, Luca, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 340)
  - Rossignol, Ph. (Philippe)
    See: Denoël (Firm), box 3, folder 77
  - Roux, Dominique de, 1963-67 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    Includes transcript of a letter and RG's correspondence
  - Roux, Dominique de, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 342-344)
    Includes list of persons who should be sent a copy of Entretiens avec Gombrowicz, a letter from unidentified person to DR, letter of DR's brother to WG
  - Roux, Dominique de, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 345-346)
    Includes transcript of a letter, letters from unidentified persons to DR, letter addressed to RG
    See also: Constantin Jelenski, box 6, folder 184
    See also: Jonathan Cape (Firm), box 6, folder 187
    See also: Allan Kosko, box 6, folder 203
    See also: Ernesto R. Sábato, Matilde Sábato, box 10, folder 356
    See also: Sugarco edizioni, box 10, folder 389
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, Dominique de Roux, box 59, folder 1510
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, Dominique de Roux, box 59, folder 1535
  - Roux, Dominique de, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 347)
    Includes letter from Manuel de Diéguez to DR, postcard with a view of Rapallo with a possible autograph of Ezra Pound
  - Rowohlt (Firm), 1959-67 (Box 9, Folder 348)
  - Royal Shakespeare Company, 1964, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 349)
  - Rudni, Silvia, 1967 Mar 12 (Box 9, Folder 350)
  - Rússovich, Alejandro, 1965 Feb 8 (Box 9, Folder 351)
    Includes French translation of WG's letter to AR
  - Rússovich, Sergio, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 352)
  - "S" general, 1961-69 (Box 10, Folder 353)
    Includes a French translation of the letter from Sociedad Anonima La Nacion
  - S. Fischer Verlag, 1959-69 (Box 10, Folder 354-355)
    Includes correspondence with royalty statements
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, S.Fischer Verlag, folder 1536
  - Sábato, Ernesto R.; Sábato, Matilde, 19[55?]-69. n.d. (Box 10, Folder 356)
    Includes postcard written jointly by Ernesto Sábato, Tadeusz ----, Jerzy Horodynski
    See also: Editorial Sudamericana, box 3, folder 93
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz's Papers, Ernesto R. Sábato, box 59, folder 1537
  - Sandauer, Artur, 1956-68, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 357-359)
    Includes AS's notes on translation of Ferdydurke and a fragment of Dziennik (photocopy of signed typescript)
    See also: Dominique de Roux, Box 9, folder 346
    See also: Series V. Writings of Others About WG, "Listy Witolda Gombrowicza do Artura Sandauera," box 111, folder 2171
  - Sanderson, Ruth, 1968 Aug 29 (Box 10, Folder 360)
  - Sanguineti, Edoardo, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 361)
  - Scherer, Olga, 1958-67 (Box 10, Folder 362)
  - Schiller-Theater (Berlin, Germany), 1964-68 (Box 10, Folder 363)
  - Schröder, Ernst, 1968 Jan 17 (Box 10, Folder 364)
  - Schmidt, Lars, 1969
    See: Théâtre Montparnasse, box 11, folder 406
  - Schostakovsky, Pablo
  - Schweizerische Radio- und Fernsehgesellshaft, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 365)
  - Seaver, Richard
    See: Grove Press, box 5, folder 149-155
  - SEBA Stichting Tot Exploitatie en Bescherming van Auteursrechten, 1964-66 (Box 10, Folder 366)
    Includes contract
    See also: Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), box 10, folder 380
  - Sebbag, George, 1967-68 (Box 10, Folder 367)
    See also: Series X. Rita Gombrowicz Papers, George Sebbag, "La raison errante," box 45, folder 1292
  - Seehaus, Günther
    See: Julliard (Firm), box 6, folder 190
  - Sédir, Georges, 1963-67, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 368)
    See also: Koukou Chanska, box 6, folder 206
  - Segalat, Roger Jean, 1966 Jun 13 (Box 10, Folder 369)
  - Serreau, Geneviève, 1961-67 (Box 10, Folder 370)
    See also: Constantin Jelenski, box 6, folder 182
  - Serreau, Geneviève, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 371)
    Includes WG's draft of a letter
    See also: Théâtre National de Chaillot, box 11, folder 407
  - Silvano d'Arborio, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 372)
    Includes a list of foreign plays produced in Italy in theatrical season 1966/67 (enclosure)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 373)
  - Sjöberg, Alf, 1966-68 (Box 10, Folder 374)
  - Sjöberg, Alf, n.d (Box 10, Folder 375)
    Includes a note about AS, newspaper cutting about AS, copies of drawings for the performance of Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda and Slub
  - Skibniewski, Mieczyslaw, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 376)
  - Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), 1963-65 (Box 10, Folder 377)
    Includes an authorisation for la Compagnie Georges Lavelli
  - Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 378)
    Includes "Bulletin de privilege"
  - Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), 1967 (Box 10, Folder 379)
    Includes am authorisation for the radio adaptation of Cosmos
  - Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), 1968 (Box 10, Folder 380)
  - Société des auteurs et compositeurs dramatiques (France), 1969 (Box 10, Folder 381)
    See also: Zwiazek Autorow i Kompozytorow "ZAIKS", box 11, folder 439
  - Soltan, Teresa, 1966-69 (Box 10, Folder 382)
  - Soprano, Edoardo
    See: Premio Marzotto Europa, box folder 308
  - Stáchová, Helena
  - Stachowicz, Izabela (Czajka), 1958-63 (Box 10, Folder 383)
  - Städtische Bühnen Dortmund, 1964-65 (Box 10, Folder 384)
  - Stauffacher, Hans Rudolf, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 385)
  - Stockholms Stadsteater
    See: Zaba Norbert, box 11, folder 432
  - Stolpe, Jan, 1966-67 (Box 10, Folder 386)
  - Stone, Shepard
  - Studio Hamburg Film Produktion, 1969, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 387)
    Includes a note containing the translation of German words
  - Stummvoll, Josef
    See: Österreichische Nationalbibliothek, box 9, folder 290
  - Subotin, Stojan
    See: Nolit (Firm)
  - Suescún, Nicolás, 1967 May 11 (Box 10, Folder 388)
  - Sugarco edizioni, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 389)
  - Svensson, Georg Vilhelm
    See: Albert Bonniers Förlag, box 1, folder 2
  - Swieczewski, Karol; Swieczewska, Maria, 1954-69, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 390-392)
    Includes French translations of some letters, RG's correpondence
  - Szubska, Barbara, 1969 May 26 (Box 11, Folder 393)
  - Szyper, Adam, 1969 May 16 (Box 11, Folder 394)
  - "T" general, 1963-68, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 395)
  - Tabbush, Bertha de, 1949 Jul 25 (Box 11, Folder 396)
    Includes RG's note on BR
  - Tagliaferri, Aldo